

David Rielo

DATE OF BIRTH: 11/10/1983

CONTACT

Nationality: Spanish

Gender: Male

Admiralengratch 101, null 1057ES Amsterdam, Netherlands



(+34) 605369049 (+31) 682782233

es.linkedin.com/in/davidrielo/

https://github.com/davidrielo

davidrielo.github.io

ABOUT ME

I'm currently Team Leader in 24i, Amsterdam Experienced in multiplatform development, also acting as operational coach Working in the past also as Freelance Art Director over Graphic Design, Branding Corporative Identity Desing & Illustration. Proud to be a huge music nerd and a digital nomad.

WORK EXPERIENCE

01/08/2018 - CURRENT

Technical Team Lead / Product Developer

24

Project: Product Team NextGen Core Framework

Technical Environment: React Native, React, ES6, webpack, babel, koitlin, swift.

Amsterdam, Netherlands

05/2015 - 07/2018

Application / Front End Developer

24

Develop custom-designed apps for Smart TV, set-top boxes and game consoles, based on customers requirements, using our powerful AppCore. These include live video, video on demand, catch-up TV, distribution of non-video content, content enrichment using interactive features (such as HbbTV or content recognition) and creating interaction between the Smart TV, game console, set-top box and other connected devices.

Projects:

Blim SmarTV VOD. Lead Developer.

VOD application service for VEO Televisa for the Mexican market. The service changed its name to Blim.

Platforms: Samsung Tizen & Orsay, LG WebOS & netcast, Sony TV (OperaTV/ AndroidTV), PSX (PS3/ PS4).

Blim (http://www.blim.com/). Blim SmartTV App

Videoland 2.0. Lead Developer.

Dutch Broadcaster. New Videoland app that will replace the current one.

Platforms: Samsung 2012 and up, PS3/PS4, LG 2012 and up, Philips 2012 high end and up, Sony 2014 and up, STB Humax H3, Panasonic 2014 and up.

Videoland (https://videoland.com/). Videoland App

Globo.com Consultancy Stream/ DRM Videotester. Lead Developer.

Consultancy project for brazilean company Globo.com to check and test the different kinds of Stream Containers and DRMs.

Platforms: Samsung 2013 and up, LG 2013 and up, Philips 2013 high end and up, Sony 2014 and up, Panasonic 2014 and up.

Videotester App

Dansk Film Skat & MinBio. Developer.

Platforms: Samsung 2012+ (including 4k), Playstation 3 and 4, LG 2012+, Philips 2012+.

Dansk Film Skat (https://www.danskfilmskat.dk/) DFS App

MinBio (https://www.minbio.dk/) MinBio App

Other Resposibilities: Madrid Office Tech Lead responsibilities, such as, evaluate new candidates knowgledge and check technical tests, make estimations and presales on new projects, set up the QA environment of the Madrid Office, evaluate and inform to the Madrid Office Operating Officer about technical improvements of the technical environment in the office.

Technical Environment: vanillajs. require.js, Grunt/ Gulp, Less, cehtml/ xhtml/ html5, webOS, Tizen, OperaTV, AndroidTV, REST, RESTful, Jenkins, VOD, Adaptative Streaming (HLS, SmoothStraming, Mpg-DASH, Widevine, DRM.

Madrid, Spain

31/10/2016 - 01/06/2017

Frelance UI Designer

http://jumptvs.com/

Design different digital products oriented to SmartTV Services.

Madrid, Spain

09/2014 - 05/2015

Lead Frontend Developer

Lextrend Information Technologies

Setting up, planning, developing and leading the frontend team in a group of application projects for LEXTREND clients.

Technical Environment: Backbone.js, Browserify.js, Common.js, Handlebars.js, Gulp, node.js, Angular, Responsive Web Design, Stylus, SASS, html5, css3, jQuery, jQuery UI, JSON, Skeleton Boilerplate, Foundation 4, Bootstrap3, REST, RESTful.

Madrid, Spain

05/2014 - 09/2014

Frontend Developer Marketing

GOWEX

Marketing department projects: Marketing Client campaigns (Microsites, Mailing, Newsletter designs, banners designs...). Manteniance and updates of corporate website (http://www.gowex.com). Design and develop of whole front end of GOWEX group websites. Redesign and implementation of new responsive WILOC channels for new company Android app.Technical Environment: Responsive Web Design, SASS, html5, css3, jQuery, jQuery UI, JSON, Angularjs, XML, INK (Zurb), Wordpress, php5.

Madrid, Spain

02/2014 - 05/2014

Frontend Developer

Custos Mobile

CLOUD POS project: Development tool in the cloud, capable of generating real-time applications for remote execution POS, magnetic stripe, EMV and Contactless, and provide these devices new functionality added value, loyalty, ticketing, marketing.

Technical Environment: Responsive Web Design Skeleton boilerplate + SASS, xhtml, css3, JSF (primefaces), jqplot, Spring WebFlow, Spring MVC, Spring Security (LDAP), jQuery, jQuery UI, Backbonejs, REST, JSON, XML, Maven, MyBatis, RabbitMQ, jboss AS 7.0.Custos Mobile website, (http://www.custosmobile.com/). Multi-language adaptation project and module adding and customization over corporate website. Technical environment: php, html5, css3. joomla 2.5.

Alcala de Henares, Spain

02/2010 - 02/2014

Web Application Developer

Omnisoft Informática

RSI Área Prepago, (http://guretruck.areaprepago.com/) y RSI Área Regalo: (http://www.tutarjetaregalo.com/): Proyect for CajaRural´s IT. Website built for RSI as B2B application for managing cash card services serving to their clients or employees through subdomains they previously offer . Technical environment: html5, css3. javascript, ajax, jQuery, JSON, XML, J2EE + EJBs, Web Services, Oracle WebLogic 10, SQL db ,pl/sql and shellscript.

BBÝA GlM/ SATE /HR Solutions: Development, implementation, maintenance and extension of functionalities of applications and web

management tools for clients such as BBVA. Technical enviroment: con EJBs, SQL db (LDAP), using pure javascript, html5, css3, Ajax, Json, Web Servicies. IBM Websphere 7.0. Eclipse Juno, IBM Rational Application Developer, o NetBeans IDE´s.SATE /HR Solutions: manager of front-end HR Self Service Solutions tool project for BBVA during the last year moving it to Responsive Web Design. Technical enviroment: xhtml/html5, xml, css3, javascript and jQuery in the front. J2EE + EJBs, struts, SQL

Madrid, Spain

09/2008 - 03/2010

EPS Lab Technician

Universidad Autonoma de Madrid

Remote Desktop with IBM Tivoli Remote Control, IBM 3270, Technical systems and network administrator profiles laboratory classroom programming at Polytechnic School of the Universidad Autónoma of Madrid.

Madrid, Spain

10/2007 - 07/2008

Student Colaboration work - web developer

Universidad Politécnica de Madrid

Developing PHP + MySQL web for an e-learning application proyect.

Application Developer e-learning / portal of educational resources and services exclusive department staff engineerings and telematic architectures on the intranet. As committed in office, implementation, modification and extension of the functionality developed in php, html and discharging records necessary for application in mySQL database with openLDAP.

Madrid, Spain

02/2003 - 07/2003

Operative Support

Vodafone Global Enterprise

Student practice job.

Enable properly high portability requests on the network that other telecom operators against vodafone performed on systems GSM and 3G servers. Logical Security. Performing Incident management also derived in the process using own management tools

Madrid, Spain

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

2010 - 2013

Three Years Certification in Design, Publicty and Illustration, Design and Applied Arts

ESDIP

Finalist at Ethnic Painting Contest 2012

2010 - 2010

Bachelor Degree Art Direction

ESDIP

2008 - 2010 - Madrid

Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.), Telecommunications Engineering (not finished)

Universidad Autónoma de Madrid

2003 - 2008

Technical Telecomunications Engeenering, Telecommunications Engineering

Universidad Politécnica de Madrid

2001 - 2003

Telecomunications and Computer Technician, Computer Systems Networking and Telecommunications

IES Moratalaz

1997 - 2001

ESO

ies Dámaso Alonso

Course Introduction to photography

LANGUAGE SKILLS

MOTHER TONGUE(S): Español

OTHER LANGUAGE(S):

Inglés

Listening Reading Spoken Spoken Writing
C1 C1 production interaction C1
B2 C1

RECOMMENDATIONS

Fernando Monroy | EDUCATION

My name is Fernando Monroy Rubio and I am teaching in ESDIP ($\mbox{Professional School of Drawing}$) from the late nineties .

David studied at the school, highlighting his commitment and quality during his career as a student. His main qualities are creativity and ingenuity. David has a great adaptability to any project, always giving his personal view .

Accepts criticism well , which implies constant willingness to learn and evolve.

In short, it has been a student with a high and constant evolution, increasing the quality of his works on each new project.

Mi nombre es Fernando Rubio Monroy y soy docente en ESDIP (Escuela Superior de Dibujo Profesional) desde finales de los noventa.

David Rielo cursó en dicha escuela destacando su implicación y calidad durante su trayectoria como alumno. Sus principales cualidades son la creatividad y el ingenio. Tiene gran capacidad de adaptación a cualquier encargo aportando siempre una visión propia. Acepta bien las críticas, lo que implica ganas constantes de aprender y evolucionar.

En definitiva, ha sido un alumno constante en su esfuerzo con una gran evolución al realizar el curso realizando trabajos cada vez de mayor calidad.

Att. Fernando Rubio Monroy

JOB-RELATED SKILLS

Job-related skills

Software Development, Graphic Design, JavaScript, ES6, html5, CSS3/CSS, Cross-browser Compatibility, Web Development, Agile Scrum, JSON, XML, Git, Framework Design, Linux, Unix, less, sass, stylus, postCSS, Photoshop, Illustrator, Sketch, InDesign.

OTHER SKILLS

Other skills

Scrum Master: Certification on PSM I at scrum.org

COURSES

Courses

Concept art and Sketching with Corel Painter 12 Implementation of eCommerce Platforms Workshop | 111-6